bitmovin.com 2019-11-30

# Bitmovin Privacy Policy - Bitmovin

Bitmovin, Inc. (“Bitmovin” or “we” or “us”) is committed to your privacy.  This Privacy Policy (“Policy”) describes how Bitmovin collects, uses and discloses your personal information when you use the Bitmovin website and domain name, any other linked pages, features, content, software applications, and any other services we offer from time to time in connection with any of the above (collectively, the “Service”) and your rights in respect of the personal information we use.

## Information Collected by Bitmovin

The Bitmovin Service is available to its customers and their users (collectively, the “users”). In order to provide the Service, Bitmovin collects information from its customers that may include personal information of its users. We also collect certain information directly from individuals.

**_Information You Provide Voluntarily._** When a user registers for an account with us, accesses our Service, or updates their profile with us, we collect certain information directly from that user, including name and email address, mailing address, phone number, billing information , purchase information, company name, job title, industry, as well as other information you may voluntarily submit to us (e.g., through support channels).

Users may login to Bitmovin using their account credentials from certain other supported service providers. You may use your Google®, Slack®, Github® or other third party login credentials we may support to sign in to Bitmovin (“SSO credentials”), we will collect and store your user ID included in your SSO credentials. We may also collect information you voluntarily supply to us regarding your personal preferences and interests. If you use your SSO credentials to access the Service, you understand that some content and/or information stored by these third party service providers associated with the SSO credentials (“Third Party Account Information”) may be transmitted into your account with us if you authorize such transmissions, and that Third Party Account Information transmitted to our Service is covered by this Policy.

**_Information We Collect Automatically._** We may automatically collect the following information about your use of our Service through cookies, web beacons, and other technologies: your domain name; your browser type and operating system; web pages you view; links you click; your IP address; the length of time you use our Services; the referring URL, or the webpage or other source, that led you to our site; ads you clicked on; search terms you have entered; access time; and any device identifier. We may combine this information with other information that we have collected about you, including, where applicable, your username, name, and other personal information. Please see the section “Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms” for more information. In addition, if you are using our player application, we collect the license key associated with the player to confirm that it is associated with a valid subscription to our Service.

**_Location Information._** In addition, we may collect different types of information about your location, including general information (e.g., IP address, zip code), and may use that information to customize the Service with location-based information and features. If you access the Service through a mobile device and you do not want your device to provide us with location-tracking information, you can disable location-tracking functions on your device, provided your device allows you to do this.

You can choose not to provide us with any or all of the information we specify or request, but then you may not be able to register with us or to take advantage of some or all of the Service.

**Information that we obtain from third party sources** : From time to time, we receive personal information about you from third party sources (including from our customers whose videos you have viewed), but only where we have checked that these third parties either have your consent or are otherwise legally permitted or required to disclose your personal information to us.

The types of information we collect from third parties include company name and number of employees and we use the information we receive from these third parties to maintain and improve the accuracy of the records we hold about you.

## How We Use Your Personal Information

We use the information that we gather about you for the following sorts of purposes:

  * To provide Service to you, to communicate with you about your use of our Service, to respond to your inquiries, to fulfill your orders, and for other customer service purposes.
  * To tailor the content and information that we may send or display to you, to offer location customization, or to otherwise personalize your experiences while using our Service.
  * For marketing and promotional purposes. For example, we may use your email address, to email you about products or information we think may interest you, in accordance with your marketing preferences. We may also use the information that we learn about you to help determine when and how to advertise our services on third party websites, advertising networks and services, or to customize how we market the Service to you.
  * To better understand how users access and use our Service, both on an aggregated and individualized basis, in order to improve our Service, respond to user preferences, and for other research and analytical purposes.
  * To diagnose service or technical problems.
  * To ensure and maintain the security of the Services.
  * As required or otherwise permitted by applicable law.
  * As otherwise described herein or as disclosed to you at the point of collection.

## 

Bitmovin shares your personal information with the following third-party recipients:

  * **_Service Providers._** In certain situations, we employ other companies and people to perform tasks on our behalf and share your information with them to provide that service, such as Google, Amplitude, Outreach.io, SalesForce, Chargebee, Chargify, Chartmogul, HubSpot, Amplitude, KISSmetrics, Intercom, Wootrics, Productboard, GotoWebinar, Buffer, Eventbrite, Github, Buffer, Slack, Greenhouse, Twitter, Facebook, LinkedIn and Zendesk. Except as stated in this privacy policy or unless we inform you otherwise, our agents do not have any right to use the personal information we share with them beyond what we deem necessary to assist us in performing such tasks.
  * **_Other Users._** Certain user profile information, including without limitation, a user’s username and any content that such user has uploaded to our website may be visible to other users you have invited to share in your account to facilitate user interaction within the Service, to address your request for our services or to otherwise enable features of the Service.
  * **_Third Party sites and Applications._** Businesses or third party websites we work with may provide services to you through the Service (either alone or jointly with us). We do not control the policies and practices of third party websites or businesses, even if they may be affiliated or partnered with us or the Service, so if you choose to take part in any transaction or service relating to a third party website or business, please review all relevant privacy and other policies of such website or business.
  * **_Affiliates._** We may disclose the personal information we collect from you to our affiliates or subsidiaries; however, if we do so, their use and disclosure of your personal information will be subject to this Policy.
  * **_Business Transactions._** We may disclose personal information in connection with any proposed purchase, merger or acquisition of any part of our business, provided that we inform the buyer it must use your personal information only for the purposes disclosed in this Privacy Policy
  * **_Legal Requirements and Protection._** Bitmovin may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law, court order, subpoena, other legal process, or if we believe that it is reasonably necessary to comply with a law, regulation or legal request; to protect the safety of any person; to address fraud, security or technical issues; or to protect Bitmovin’s rights or property.
  * **_Aggregate and/or Non-identified Information._** Bitmovin may disclose aggregate and/or anonymized information collected through the Service and the use and disclosure of such aggregate and/or anonymized information by Bitmovin or third parties is not subject to any restrictions under this Policy.
  * **_Others_**. Bitmovin may disclose your personal information to any other person with your consent to the disclosure.

## Our Use of Cookies and Other Tracking Mechanisms

We and our third party service providers use cookies and other tracking mechanisms to track information about your use of our Service. We may combine this information with other personal information we collect from you (and our third party service providers may do so on our behalf).

**_Cookies._** Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser for record-keeping purposes. Some cookies allow us to make it easier for you to navigate our Service, while others are used to enable a faster log-in process, to allow us to track your activities on our Service, or to otherwise enable Service features. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but if you prefer, you can edit your browser options to block them in the future. The Help portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to prevent your computer from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. Visitors to our site who disable cookies will be able to browse certain areas of the site, but some features may not function.

**_Clear GIFs, pixel tags and other technologies._** Clear GIFs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on your computer’s hard drive, clear GIFs are embedded invisibly on web pages. We may use clear GIFs (also known as web beacons, web bugs or pixel tags), in connection with our site to, among other things, track the activities of site visitors, help us manage content and compile statistics about site usage. We or our service providers may also use clear GIFs in HTML emails to our customers to help us track email response rates, identify when our emails are viewed and track whether our emails are forwarded.

**_LSOs._** We or third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features of the Service or to display advertising based upon your tracked activity may use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) using technologies such as HTML5 or Flash to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To learn about managing Flash LSOs, please click [here](https://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html).

**_Third-party Analytics._** We use third party analytics tools, such as Google Analytics, to collect, monitor and analyze collected information in order to improve functionality and user-friendliness, and to better tailor the Services to our visitors’ needs. Accordingly, usage data is shared with Google, which has its own [privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en) addressing how it uses such information. We encourage you to review this privacy policy to understand how Google uses such information.

## California Do Not Track Disclosure

**_Currently, the analytics portion of the Service recognizes browser “do-not-track” requests, but other portions of the Service do not._** You may, however, disable certain tracking as discussed above (e.g., by disabling cookies). For more information about tracking, please click [here](https://allaboutdnt.com/).

## Interest-Based Advertising

We use third parties such as network advertisers to serve advertisements on third-party websites or other media (e.g. social networking platforms). For example, we use Google, LinkedIn, Facebook and Twitter to serve advertisements on third-party websites. This enables us and these third parties to target advertisements to you for products and services in which you might be interested. Third-party ad network providers, advertisers, sponsors and/or traffic measurement services may use cookies, JavaScript, web beacons (including clear GIFs), LSOs and other tracking technologies to measure the effectiveness of their ads and to personalize advertising content to you. These third-party cookies and other technologies are governed by each third party’s specific privacy policy, not this one. We may provide these third-party advertisers with information, including personal information, about you.

Users in the United States may opt out of many third-party ad networks. For example, you may go to the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) Consumer Choice Page for information about opting out of interest-based advertising and choices regarding having information used by DAA companies. You may also go to the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) Consumer Opt-Out Page for information about opting out of interest-based advertising and choices regarding having information used by NAI members.

Users in the European Union may also opt out of many third-party ad networks. For example, you may go to the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance (“EDAA”) Your Online Choices Page for information about opting out of interest-based advertising and choices regarding having information used by EDAA members.

Opting out from one or more companies listed on the DAA Consumer Choice Page, the NAI Consumer Opt-Out Page or the EDAA Your Online Choices Page will opt you out from those companies’ delivery of interest-based content or ads to you, but it does not mean you will no longer receive any advertising through our Site or on other websites. You may continue to receive advertisements, for example, based on the particular website that you are viewing (i.e., contextually based ads). Also, if your browsers are configured to reject cookies when you opt out on the DAA, NAI, or EDAA-related websites, your opt out may not be effective. Additional information is available on the DAA’s website at www.aboutads.info, the NAI’s website at[ www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/), and the EDAA’s website at www.youronlinechoices.com/goodpractice.

## Legal Basis For Our Use (EEA visitors only)

If you are a resident from the European Economic Area, our legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described above will depend on the personal information concerned and the specific context in which we collect it.

However, we will normally collect personal information from you only where we have your consent to do so, where we need the personal information to perform a contract with you, or where the processing is in our legitimate interests and not overridden by your data protection interests or fundamental rights and freedoms.  In some cases, we may also have a legal obligation to collect personal information from you.

If we ask you to provide personal information to comply with a legal requirement or to perform a contract with you, we will make this clear at the relevant time and advise you whether the provision of your personal information is mandatory or not (as well as of the possible consequences if you do not provide your personal information).

Similarly, if we collect and use your personal information in reliance on our legitimate interests (or those of any third party), we will make clear to you at the relevant time what those legitimate interests are.

If you have questions about or need further information concerning the legal basis on which we collect and use your personal information for any specific processing activity, please contact us at office@bitmovin.com.

## Additional Notice for Canadian Residents

Canadian residents may have additional rights under Canadian law. Please see the information provided by the [Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada](https://www.priv.gc.ca/en/about-the-opc/publications/guide_ind/) for additional details.

You, and we, confirm that it is our wish that this Privacy Policy and all other related policies be drawn up in English. Vous reconnaissent avoir exigé la rédaction en anglais du présent document ainsi que tous les documents qui s’y rattachent.

## Security

We have implemented appropriate physical and organizational security measures to protect the information we collect from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction such as limiting access to select employees and contractors who have a need to know this information for purposes of their job, encrypting data in transit, encrypting certain sensitive information (such as passwords) at rest, and employee training on privacy and security issues. Please be aware that despite our best efforts, no data security measures can guarantee 100% security. You should take steps to protect against unauthorized access to your password, phone, and computer by, among other things, signing off after using a shared computer, choosing a robust password that nobody else knows or can easily guess, and keeping your log-in and password private. We are not responsible for any lost, stolen, or compromised passwords or for any activity on your account via unauthorized password activity.

## Transfer Personal Information to the United States

If you are located outside of the United States, please note that your personal information will be transferred to and processed in the United States which may not have the same level of data protection as your home country.  We have taken appropriate safeguards to require that your personal information will remain protected in accordance with this Privacy Policy. These include implementing the European Commission’s Standard Contractual Clauses for transfers of personal information with our third party service providers and partners and further details can be provided upon request.

## Access to your Personal Information and Your Privacy Rights

Through the Account page of the Bitmovin website, you may access, and, in some cases, edit or delete the following information you have provided to us: name, company, phone number, email address and billing information.

The information you can view and update may change as the Service changes. If you have any questions about viewing or updating information we have on file about you, please contact us at office@bitmovin.com.

**Access, correct update or request deletion**. If you wish to access, correct, update or request deletion of your personal information that you may not access directly on the Bitmovin website, you can do so at any time by contacting us at privacy@bitmovin.com.

**Object to processing, restrict processing, or request portability**. In addition, if you are a resident of the European Union, you can object to processing of your personal information, ask us to restrict processing of your personal information or request portability of your personal information. Again, you can exercise these rights by contacting us at privacy@bitmovin.com.

**Opt-out**. You have the right to opt-out of marketing communications we send you at any time.  You can exercise this right by clicking on the “unsubscribe” or “opt-out” link in the marketing e-mails we send you.  To opt-out of other forms of marketing or data collection activities, then please contact us at privacy@bitmovin.com. It may take up to 10 business days for us to process your opt-out request.

**Withdraw consent**. Similarly, if we have collected and processed your personal information with your consent, then you can withdraw your consent at any time.  Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.

**Right to complain**. You have the right to complain to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your personal information.  For more information, please contact your local data protection authority. (Contact details for data protection authorities in the European Economic Area are available[ here](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm).)

We respond to all requests we receive from individuals wishing to exercise their data protection rights in accordance with applicable data protection laws.

## Children’s Privacy

Our Service is not designed for children under 16, and Bitmovin does not want to collect and does not seek to collect personal information from children under 16 or knowingly allow such persons to register with the Service. If we discover that we have collected personal information from a child under 16, we will take steps to remove that information from our systems. If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 16, please contact us at office@bitmovin.com.

## Links to Third-Party Websites

We are not responsible for the practices employed by third-party websites linked to or from the Service, nor the information or content contained therein. Please remember that when you use a link to go from the Service to a third-party website, our Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any third-party website, including those that have a link on our website or Service, is subject to that third-party website’s own rules and policies.

## Data retention

We retain personal information we collect from you where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (for example, to provide you with a service you have requested or to comply with applicable legal, tax or accounting requirements).

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information or you have requested we delete your information, we will either delete or anonymize it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

## Updates to this Policy

We may amend this Policy from time to time, so please be sure to check back periodically. Use of information we collect now is subject to the Policy in effect at the time such information is used. If we make any changes to this Policy that materially affect our practices with regard to the personal information we have previously collected from you, we will endeavor to notify you in advance of such change by posting an announcement on our Service or contacting you directly via email or other means. If we are required by applicable data protection laws to seek your consent to any changes in use of your personal information described in our updated Privacy Policy, then we will do so.

## Contact Us

If you have any questions about our privacy practices or this Policy, please contact us at [privacy@bitmovin.com](mailto:office@bitmovin.com) or by mail at Bitmovin, Inc., Attn: Stefan Lederer, 41 Drumm Street, San Francisco, CA 94111, USA.

Our Data Protection Officer, Christopher Mueller, can be contacted at

[christopher.mueller@bitmovin.com](mailto:christopher.mueller@bitmovin.com).

Bitmovin has appointed Bitmovin GmbH to be its representative in the EEA. You can contact them directly regarding the processing of your information by Bitmovin, by email at privacy@bitmovin.com or by post to: Bitmovin GmbH, Attn: Privacy Team, Schleppe Platz 7, 9020 Klagenfurt, Austria.

Last updated: 22 May 2018
